expediaaffiliate.com 2019-08-31

# EPS Privacy Policy - Expedia Partner Solutions

_Effective 08/09/2019_  

The Privacy Policy for Expedia Partner Solutions (EPS) applies to any information provided or collected through this EPS website, any application on a social media, and other website provided by EPS, 160 Greentree Drive, Suite 101, Dover, Delaware 19904. 

We value your trust, and the security and confidentiality of the personal information you provide to us is a high priority with us. Please read this policy to learn about our privacy practices.  We generally describe below personal information related to the travel technology, supply and support services provided by EPS ("Services"); however, the relevant site providing the Services will have available the detailed description applicable to travelers and users of the Services. 

  * **_What information we collect_**
  * **_How we use personal information_**
  * **_With whom we share personal information_**
  * **_Your choices on personal information_**
  * **_Cookies and other technologies_**
  * **_How we protect personal information_**
  * **_External links_**
  * **_International transfer of personal information_**
  * **_Data Retention_**
  * **_Changes to this Privacy Policy_**
  * **_How you can contact us_**

### **  
What information we collect**

_Information Collected on this Website_. We receive and store any information you enter on our website or give us in any other way. This includes information that can identify you (“personal information”), including your first and last name, email addresses and company.  

_Information from Other Sources_. We automatically collect some information about the computer or device used to visit our websites. For example, we will collect IP address, Web browser software (such as Firefox, Safari, or Internet Explorer), and referring website.

_Information Collected from our Services_.  For the Services that EPS provides, additional information may be collected to enable the provision of the Services, including names of the traveler and their companions and required government-issued identification, plus information on contact, billing, loyalty program, and travel preferences. 

### **  
How we use personal information**

_For information collected on this Website_ , if you agree, we will send you information about EPS and the benefits of becoming an EPS partner.

_For information collected from our Services_ , such information is generally used to fulfill the Services requested, enable the Services, update loyalty program information and communicate with the users of and others related to the Services.  Other processing activities include: manage traveler account; process payment; send notification on reviews; customize user experience with the Services; prevent, investigate and resolve illegal/prohibited activities; and conduct our business such as enforce the terms of use and other agreements.

### **  
With whom we share your information**

_For information collected on this Website_ :  With your appropriate consent, we may share your information with the following entities:

  * Social media providers and analytics platforms – We will only share anonymous information in order to assess the performance of our site. When you access certain social media features through our website such as LinkedIn advertising, you are sharing information with the social media provider and the information you share will be governed by their privacy policies (including that we may access such information via the social media provider). You may be able to modify your privacy settings for these social media providers. Please consult the privacy policy of the relevant social media provider for further information.

We also may share your information:

  * With third party service providers who support our business.  We share information necessary for them to perform the services, require them to protect the data, and do not permit the service providers to share or use the information for another purpose.
  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * When we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of our company, this website or our Apps, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Service and other agreements.

Additionally, _for Information collected from our Services_ , we share certain information with 

  * our affiliated group of companies (listed at expediagroup.com); they follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described here; and
  * travel suppliers to fulfill and communicate about the travel reservations and Services.  We may share anonymous reviews with hotel suppliers.

### **  
Your choices on personal information**

Your information collected on this Website can be updated by completing an embedded website form. New submissions tied to the same email address will update your existing contact record.  You can also reach us at the information in the “How to Contact Us” section to access the information we hold on you. 

_Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms_. Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to websites with which the browser communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. Participants in the leading Internet standards-setting organization that is addressing this issue are in the process of determining what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals. We currently do not take action in response to these signals. If and when a final standard is established and accepted, we will reassess how to respond to these signals.

### **  
Cookies and other technologies**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit almost all websites. Cookies do not generally recognize you personally and are not harmful to your computer or mobile device. They are used by websites you visit in order to improve your experience on the website, to provide us with analytics information that will help us improve our website generally, and to collect information about travel destinations of interest to you so that you may see travel ads more relevant to you.

For instance, we use cookies on our sites to allow you to login without having to type your login name each time. Other cookies help us to understand what did and didn’t interest you about our websites so we can provide you with features that are more relevant and useful to you next time you visit. We and some of our partners also use cookies on our sites to measure the effectiveness of advertising on our site and how visitors use our sites.

For more detailed information about the cookies that we and our partners serve through our website, please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://expediapartnersolutions.com/cookie-policy). Alternatively, if have any other questions about our use of cookies or other technologies, please email us using our customer service and feedback form and we’ll do our best to help.

### **  
How we protect your information**

We want you to feel confident about using this website, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no website can guarantee security, we have implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect the personal information you provide to us. 

### **  
External links**

If any part of this website links you to other sites, those sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

### **  
Transfer of personal information outside your country**

The personal information we collect, or is collected on our behalf, may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you reside.  Specifically, the servers of our Services and this Website are located in the US, and our group companies and third-party service providers operate around the world.  This means that when we collect your personal information, we may process it in any of these countries which may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective). 

###    
_Privacy Shield Certification_

We have self-certified compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the European Union, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom. We have certified that we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfers, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Principles and to view our certification, please visit [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).

We will only process personal information in ways that are compatible with the purposes outlined above in this Privacy Policy (or those you later authorize). Before using your personal information for materially different purposes or disclosing it to independent third parties, we will provide you with the opportunity to opt out. Further choices and means you have for limiting the use and disclosure of your personal information are set out in the “Your information choices” section below

As explained in this Privacy Policy, we may provide your personal information to third parties who perform services on our behalf. If we transfer personal information received under the Privacy Shield to a third party agent or service provider and they process your personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, we will remain liable under the Privacy Shield unless we can prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your personal information in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

You may have the right to access personal information that we hold about you and request that we correct, amend or delete it if it is inaccurate or processed in violation of the Privacy Shields.

If you have any inquiries or complaints about our handling of your personal information under the Privacy Shields, you should first contact us at privacy@expedia.com, and we will respond to your inquiry promptly. If we are unable to satisfactorily resolve your complaint, or we fail to acknowledge your complaint in a timely fashion, we have further committed to cooperate and comply with the panel of European data protection authorities (DPAs), the Swiss Federal Data Protection, and Information Commissioner in the resolution of any Privacy Shield complaints. Individuals may also have the opportunity under certain conditions to invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding the Privacy Shield not resolved by the above mechanisms. See [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction) for additional information about binding arbitration.

For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Privacy Shield frameworks, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission.

### **  
Data Retention**

We retain the personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize the data or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

We will anonymize or aggregate your data if we intend to use it for analytical purposes or trend analysis over longer periods. 

### **  
Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the email address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our website.

### **  
How you can contact us**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please email us or write to us at:

_Email_ :   

_Post_ :              
160 Greentree Drive  
Suite 101  
Dover, Delaware  19904   
USA
